SUSAN EVANS

UX Designer + Developer

susanev.com hello@susanev.com (206) 395-8146

Three years experience leading UX Design and Research. Ten years experience innovating in the computer science education space.

I have a diverse background in UX Design and code and am passionate about improving the human experience by combining deep technical and design knowledge to craft digital experiences.

I love solving challenging problems in diverse teams while using user-centered practices.

SKILLS

Design	Tools
Rapid prototyping	Sketch
Wireframing	Axure RP
UI design	Illustrator
Interaction design	Indesign
Web design	Photoshop

Programming

3	
Java	Competitive analysis
Python	Survey Design
Ruby on Rails	Interviews
JavaScript	Usability studies
HTML & CSS	Participatory Design

Research

WORK EXPERIENCE

User Experience Designer

University of Washington LiY! Feb 2014 – Mar 2016

Designed and usability tested a tool for faculty across the nation to use when creating workshops focused on the advancement of women and underrepresented groups in engineering fields.

Web Designer

PSCSTA

Mar 2014 – Jun 2015

Led the redesign of a website for computer science teachers and students, which included user research, usability studies, implementation and evaluation. Improving access and awareness in the community.

User Researcher

Ubi Interactive

Dec 2014 – Mar 2015

Collaborated in a student team to conduct user research and usability studies on Ubi's software installation process. All of our recommendations were implemented by Ubi.

Computer Science Lecturer

University of Washington CSE

Mar 2016 – Present

Design and teach undergraduate and graduate introductory programming courses using a variety of languages including Java, Processing and p5.js.

Computer Science Instructor

Seattle Public Schools

Sep 2011 – Sep 2015

Led the creation of a rigorous, supportive, 4-year cs program in an ethnically diverse and low-income South Seattle school, which emphasized authentic learning, exploration, and community involvement.

EDUCATION

University of Washington

MS in Human Centered Design & Engineering Graduated Jun 2016

University of Arizona

BS in Computer Science and Mathematics Graduated Dec 2008